LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate the face of light
Save your tears for the day
when our pain is far behind
on your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
An intruder?
Viruses have infiltrated the firewall.
The infection is spreading.
The antibody is experiencing compatibility
conflict. The infection is spreading.
The enemy has penetrated the outer firewall.
Increase allocation to the peripheral defence lines.
Have decoys deal with the infected areas; discard them!
Updating virus analysis: cannibalisation in progress;
fourteen types have been neutralised,
two types are still active,
and one type remains unidentified.
What do you mean, "unidentified"?
Identify it!
Virus is inert and unresponsive, according to preliminary analysis results.
It is most likely a decoy.
Run a diagnosis with a different version of the antibody.
Do not let the enemy observe our response protocol.
The enemy has begun to assume control over the broadcast relay unit.
We are unable to physically disconnect the circuit.
The virus is propagating.
Damn it, who are these cyber attackers?
The primary defence line has been reduced by 60%.
Request backup support from Poseidon's Decatoncale!
The Hope
Named Despair
Damn, we're too late.
Call an ambulance. Rescuing the injured comes first.
Get an ambulance, quick!
We're at the Niihama 3 shopping mall -
we'll need at least five of them!
It's the same, no doubt about it.
He blew himself up, eh...
Yeah, he used plastic explosives rigged with nails and screws.
Damn it, what is this whole "indiscriminate
terrorism after a warning" thing about?
Seems like this is all about the size of terror.
The size of terror?
Yeah. As is the case with the Individual Eleven,
after first releasing a warning,
the terrorists end up repeating
indiscriminate suicide bombings.
This type is troublesome; for them, the
significance of terrorism lies in the act itself.
Then you're saying that there will be another act of terrorism?
If we are to believe their warning, yes.
Damn... What the hell is happening in this country?
Something's starting to go haywire, isn't it?
You're probably right. We can't keep up the way things are going.
Chief, there's no way we can catch up the way things are now.
Are there any hints in the warning as to
where and when the terrorist attacks will take place?
As of now, the only information we have is
an e-mail saying that five terrorist attacks involving
suicide bombers will occur today in Niihama.
It was sent to the Prefectural Police.
If this case is the same type as the
attacks that occurred last week in Fukuoka,
there is no doubt that the final attack will also occur here in Niihama.
Transfer jurisdiction over this attack to the Prefectural
Police, and prevent the next attack from occurring at any cost.
Are you asking us to detain every single cyborg in Niihama?
Even though this seems indiscriminate,
there must be some pattern to it.
Roger.
By the way, where's the Major when we need her?
She's on a classified infiltration mission.
A classified infiltration mission, huh?
We'll leave this to the local police and
the old man - we're moving out!
Bomer, report if you find anything.
What's this about human bombs in the first place?
This country is not an anarchy under enforced rule.
It means things are no longer so
peaceful that you can say stuff like that.
Not even in this country.
True... The refugee issue is a powder keg ready to blow.
That the individualists have got this radical may be
the fault of a government with so uncertain a course.
I get it...
It could be the refugees...
I'd totally forgotten that!
Chief! Please look into the suspects from last week's
Fukuoka incident and the past few hours' attacks!
Their bodies are barely intact.
What we know is that they had a relatively high
percentage of cybernetic components and not much more.
No, it's not about that.
The IR system and surveillance cameras must have
recorded them while they were still alive.
I want all this footage to be collected.
All right.
Let's try it.
What's this about?
This sort of stuff can't happen all that often on such a large scale,
even if people are forced by others or by their superiors.
Suicide bombing is an act of terrorism you resort to
when you have no further hope in your life.
Chief, are things going all right?
It seems as though we're really behind.
We will get to the next one without fail!
And how are you doing on your end?
The Tachikomas are doing fine in agent mode.
There is almost no need to consider any loss
in efficiency resulting from physical distance.
While there will be no victory,
I don't think there will be defeat, either.
Right, right!
Don't go too far.
I wonder.
I'll try to rein myself in, though.
Tachikoma, is the Omni-sense mask array working?
We've already finished investigating the shortest route!
Mask array activation is complete!
I've disabled the emergency
lock down mechanism in the security room.
The enemy's offensive firewall consists of 512 types.
It is being deployed in Level 1.
The defence line has been restored by 70%. Continuing struggle for 22%, 8%...
403 types are of the destructive mobile variety.
82 types are composite parts.
27 types are explosives and decoys.
The backup firewall from the Decatoncale has reached an activation of 97% of maximum.
It withstood the attack...
If you let AIs handle everything, you'll
get outsmarted by cats and mice, too.
A report from the cyber police has arrived.
They have determined the individuals
who presumably carried out suicide bombings
from the footage retrieved from
locations where acts of terrorism occurred.
These are their images.
I see.
Bomer, what about your analysis of the explosives?
Judging from the residue, C-4 was employed in all four cases.
Can you profile the source or the manufacturing process used?
Note: Spring-8 is a research particle accelerator
If I were able to bring all of this into
Spring-8, I'd be able to find out more.
I see.
Chief, I got some interesting data on the
stores that were destroyed by the bomb.
The first two buildings were being
used as gathering places for particularists.
The next two were also owned by an organisation using
the Refugee Special Treatment Act as a cover for profit.
This restaurant's background is similar to the rest, too.
It seems Batou's hunch might be right on the money.
Have the Prefectural Police's Public
Safety Division figured that out?
No matches were found in their database.
I see.
Contact the Prefectural Police immediately.
Have their police officers patrol any
gathering locales for particularists
as well as offices and shops operated by mob-related
organisations profiting from the Refugee Special Treatment Act.
If they find anyone about twenty years old
who is from a refugee camp, they should
question them, regardless of their gender.
Tell them to be especially careful with anyone who
has a high percentage of cybernetic components.
Understood.
So it is the refugees.
I hadn't expected that. I'd think the
citizens would have had more issues with them.
That's why these individualists, the
Individual Eleven, emerged, right?
And now, we have another
bunch that snapped over them?
Well, I guess that's one way to put it.
We should assume that the refugee
"powder keg" has already been ignited.
Dying in order to send a message out...
It's abnormal.
What were the time intervals between
each of the cases, from the first to the last?
The warning was sent out exactly at noon.
Then, the first attack occurred
thirteen minutes later.
The second attack occurred
thirty-eight minutes after the first.
The third attack happened after a bit of a
breather, approximately two hours later at 3:23.
The fourth attack happened after
an even longer interval, at 7:11.
There should be a greater time
interval before the next one.
In serial suicide bombing terrorism, the ones
whose resolve is firmest go first, one by one.
Let's hope that there's still time left
before the next suicide bombing.
Man, you're really knowledgeable
about the more extreme cases.
Can I ask you something?
What?
If their intent is to generate terror,
I'd think it'd be more effective
to not have a bomb warning.
Why do you think they sent it out?
Who knows.
Could it be that they want someone to know, maybe?
To know what their final actions were?
It's as I'd expected.
I've confirmed that they had strong
ties with Poseidon from Gouda's history,
but to think it's all been reduced to
a manual to this extent...
A trap...?
Or...
Deploy the root array along three axes.
Have all offensive firewalls on standby.
Deployment complete!
Back me up with full functionality.
Be careful of compound viruses.
Okaaay!
All right, invest all senses
into the thickest firewall.
Inject the Chroma file into the
system before the enemy arrives.
Set up an advanced combat formation
with all eight arrays.
All homing mines that are equipped
with the virus array are now active!
Suppression of all twelve
SAT-MAN cyberbrains complete!
Good. Perform a final safety
check on the perimeter.
Confirmed activation of the action control
virus that was injected into the cyberbrains
of forty-five security department staff members.
Full range of offensive
firewalls is also operational.
There is no conflict between their functions.
Good. Our time expires when they discover the
freeze on the security department staff members.
You will monitor the forty-five cyberbrains.
If we're discovered, notify me immediately.
Roger that!
Is something wrong, sir?
No, there's nothing wrong.
So, this is the Decatoncale
I've always heard rumours about.
It seems to have constructed a virtual persona from
vast amounts of data and is running a simulation.
Who are you?
I am Gouda Kazundo.
I have previously been involved with the radioactive
dust removal and molecular engineering robotics
projects at Dai-Nippon Giken.
Radioactive dust removal...
He must be referring to the Japanese Miracle.
As a technician?
Of course not.
My brain is specialised in linguistic ability.
After the two world wars,
this country was able to regain its status
as an economic power after implementing
the radioactive dust removal method,
which was developed under my direction.
I was also supposed to join the uppermost
echelons of society at the same time.
However, just as this country was unable to gain a
significant foothold in the international community,
I was unable to acquire a
significant status in the social system here.
You mean, society did not provide concrete
recognition to the individual who was all talk?
I discovered long ago that this society
suffers from a fatal structural defect.
And that is?
The mutation of information that
should not mutate in principle,
and the illusory originality called individuality
can easily trigger synchronisation
in the current societal system.
I have named this
"An Act of Creation in the Name of Consumption."
Sounds like a conclusion an individual
who withdrew into the net would reach.
The Stand Alone Complex?
Fortunately, I had an extremely
strong tolerance for solitude.
However, it took me a very long time to realise
the very attributes I was born with were making the system
withhold proper recognition for the impact I made on society.
In other words, you had an inferiority complex.
No. My very existence was problematic.
Personas that are desired by the system itself
definitely exist in society, and people hunger for them.
And yet, they are almost
sinfully unaware of this fact.
Are you satisfied with who you are now?
Far more than I expected I would be.
Do you know that the ghost, whose existence,
unlike the body's, is only confirmed paradoxically,
actually changes in accordance
with changes to the body?
Who knows?
Although, there was apparently some theorist who saw a
personal raison d'etre in revolutions and carried one out.
Patrick Sylvestre, eh?
I have committed myself to his theories before.
I admired heroes and truly wanted to have charisma.
I am someone who should be leading others.
That thought has existed within
me as long as I can remember.
In the end, my body prevented
me from achieving that end.
However, fate was on my side.
My body was transformed by an accident that left me
wandering the line between life and death,
and then my ghost happened to change as well.
Just as the thinker acquired a mission by
encountering a revolution, I also acquired a mission.
A mission to restructure
the system called the State.
An advocate of national reorganisation,
or a megalomaniac?
Right now, what this nation desires is to recreate a state
of Xanadu that can only exist by consuming another.
By accident, this nation has
realised this in the past.
Those without a motive continue
to desire this, unaware.
I merely provide them with it.
And then you'll become a hero?
I no longer wish for that.
My role is to produce the hero.
To create an activist who will voice and carry out
what those without a motive yearn for,
yet cannot say out loud themselves.
So, this Xanadu at the end of consumption -
you mean Japan under the Cold War?
If so, then who is this hero
you are saying you will produce?
The Individual Eleven?
Oh no!
Hey. What's going on?
Hey, contact the security department.
A cyber attacker has infiltrated the system.
They took more time than I thought...
Major, they discovered our infiltration!
Got it.
Then, are the enemies of this
"hero" you speak of the refugees?
By making them imagined enemies,
you manipulate the citizens' thoughts.
Isn't that it?
Thought manipulation is necessary.
At times, the law must be bent.
The end justifies the means.
That is a philosophy that applies to
terrorists and democratic states alike.
You're saying that expelling the
refugees is a national consensus?
Modesty is one of our people's virtues.
Major!
I know.
Last question. What do you think about Section 9?
Section 9... let's see.
The chain reaction of hatred that
was created by absence will not stop.
Section 9 will suffer in between the national consensus
of the people and their own sense of justice.
Major, you will be in danger
if you don't drop soon!
Out of time.
We've just arrived at Gate No. 6.
When the local police questioned the individual,
the terrorist apparently ran into the
subway and threatened to detonate herself.
I managed to get the train stopped, but it
has entered the station with passengers inside.
Stop her, no matter what!
You go that way!
Where is she?!
I've found the terrorist.
As we'd expected, she's a refugee.
Nobody move!
All right, don't make any moves.
Put your hands behind your back.
That's right. We won't do anything.
Slowly, now... stay calm.
Get out of my way!
Why did you shoot?
You idiot!
It's the fuse!
Call an ambulance.
Since she has explosives packed inside of
her gut, she'll need to be in total isolation.
R-Roger!
Security section!
Check inside the building immediately!
The cyber attacker appears to have
infiltrated the premises in person, using a decoy.
What were the security staff doing?
Restart the SAT-MAN!
Check the virus.
Once you restart the firewall array,
transfer jurisdiction to Poseidon
and let them handle the rest.
The attacker will not come here again.
So, we managed to get the last one.
Barely.
This will have lasting effects.
This is a declaration of war from the refugees.
Batou's hunch is, unfortunately, correct.
The Individual Eleven are most probably
individualists that were "produced" by Gouda.
Their goal is a refugee uprising.
The compromise will probably be to create an
autonomous region for the refugees within this nation.
Up to now, we have suffered total defeat.
The "chain reaction of hatred"
Gouda spoke of has definitely begun.
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
and singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside
(Our time is now)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
(the time is now)
I see inside,
see the light now ever holding me.
(the time is now)
All the truth,
(All the truth)
all I need,
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within the shell.